<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:3000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-07T21:15:18+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Programmingera</title><subtitle>Welcome to ProgrammingEra - Your Premier Destination for All Things Coding, Programming, and Technology. Stay ahead of the curve with expert insights, tutorials, and the latest industry news</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to Become an Ethical Hacker in 2023: A Step-by-Step Guide, Career Opportunities, and Internships in India</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/how-to-become-an-ethical-hacker-in-2023-a-step-by-step-guide-career-opportunities-and-internships-in-india/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Become an Ethical Hacker in 2023: A Step-by-Step Guide, Career Opportunities, and Internships in India" /><published>2023-03-07T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-03-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/how-to-become-an-ethical-hacker-in-2023-a-step-by-step-guide-career-opportunities-and-internships-in-india</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/how-to-become-an-ethical-hacker-in-2023-a-step-by-step-guide-career-opportunities-and-internships-in-india/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/pexels-tima-miroshnichenko-5380642.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>As technology continues to advance, the need for cybersecurity professionals, particularly ethical hackers, is increasing. An ethical hacker, also known as a white hat hacker, is a computer security expert who utilizes their hacking skills to identify vulnerabilities in a company’s computer systems and networks.</p>

<p>Becoming an ethical hacker in 2023 can be a rewarding and exciting career choice. With the increase in cyber threats and attacks, there is a high demand for skilled professionals who can protect networks and systems. In this comprehensive guide, we will provide you with a step-by-step guide on how to become an ethical hacker, career opportunities, and internships in India.</p>

<h2 id="step-1-understanding-ethical-hacking">Step 1: Understanding Ethical Hacking</h2>

<p>Before embarking on the journey to become an ethical hacker, it is essential to understand the concept of ethical hacking. Ethical hacking involves identifying vulnerabilities in systems and networks and fixing them before malicious attackers can exploit them. This involves using the same techniques and tools as cybercriminals but for ethical purposes.</p>

<h2 id="step-2-education-and-training">Step 2: Education and Training</h2>

<p>To become an ethical hacker, you need to have a strong foundation in computer science or information technology. A bachelor’s degree in computer science, cybersecurity, or a related field is an excellent starting point. Additionally, gaining certifications such as Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH) or Offensive Security Certified Professional (OSCP) can help you gain expertise in ethical hacking.</p>

<h2 id="step-3-build-practical-skills">Step 3: Build Practical Skills</h2>

<p>Practical skills are crucial for any aspiring ethical hacker. You can gain practical experience by participating in bug bounty programs or by setting up a virtual lab to practice penetration testing. Joining a community of like-minded individuals or participating in online forums can also help you build practical skills.</p>

<h2 id="step-4-internships-in-india">Step 4: Internships in India</h2>

<p>Internships are an excellent way to gain practical experience and build a network of contacts in the field of ethical hacking. Several organizations in India offer internships in cybersecurity and ethical hacking, including the Indian Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-In) and cybersecurity firms such as Lucideus and K7 Computing.</p>

<h2 id="step-5-career-opportunities">Step 5: Career Opportunities</h2>

<p>Ethical hacking is a promising career choice with various job opportunities in India. Companies, including IT consulting firms, financial institutions, and healthcare organizations, require ethical hackers to safeguard their systems and networks. Job titles in this field include Penetration Tester, Security Analyst, and Security Consultant.</p>

<p>Conclusion</p>

<p>Becoming an ethical hacker in 2023 requires a strong foundation in computer science, practical skills, and expertise in cybersecurity. With a growing demand for cybersecurity professionals, ethical hacking is an excellent career choice with promising job opportunities. By following the steps outlined in this guide, you can embark on a successful career in ethical hacking.</p>]]></content><author><name>programmingera</name></author><category term="Ethical Hacking" /><category term="skills" /><category term="featured" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:3000/assets/images/pexels-tima-miroshnichenko-5380642.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:3000/assets/images/pexels-tima-miroshnichenko-5380642.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Creating Your First Website for Beginners: From Github to Netlify</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/creating-your-first-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating Your First Website for Beginners: From Github to Netlify" /><published>2023-03-03T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/creating-your-first-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/creating-your-first-website/"><![CDATA[<div>
<img src="/assets/images/photo-1498050108023-c5249f4df085.avif" alt="coding" />
    <div class="min-h-[20px] flex flex-col items-start gap-4 whitespace-pre-wrap"><div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light"><p>Creating your first website can be a daunting task, but with the right resources and tools, it can be an exciting and rewarding experience. In this blog post, we'll walk you through the process of creating a simple website for beginners and deploying it on Netlify.</p><p>Step 1: Setting up your development environment
Before you start building your website, you'll need to set up your development environment. You'll need a text editor to write your code, a web browser to test your website, and Git to manage your code.</p><p>For this tutorial, we recommend using Visual Studio Code as your text editor and Google Chrome as your web browser. Git comes pre-installed on most operating systems, but if you don't have it installed, you can download it from the official website.</p><p>Step 2: Creating your website
Once you have your development environment set up, it's time to create your website. For this tutorial, we'll create a simple website that displays a heading and a paragraph.</p><p>First, create a new folder on your computer and name it "my-website". Then, open Visual Studio Code and create a new file in the "my-website" folder. Name the file "index.html" and add the following code:</p>
<pre>
<code>
  &lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
  &lt;html&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
	&lt;title&gt;My Website&lt;/title&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
	&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to my website&lt;/h1&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;This is a paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/body&gt;
  &lt;/html&gt;
</code>
</pre>

<p>This code creates a basic HTML page with a heading and a paragraph. Save the file and open it in your web browser to see the result.</p><p>Step 3: Pushing your website to GitHub
Now that you've created your website, it's time to push it to GitHub. GitHub is a platform for hosting and managing your code repositories.</p><p>First, create a new repository on GitHub. Name the repository "my-website" and make it public. Then, go back to Visual Studio Code and open the terminal.</p><p>Navigate to the "my-website" folder by typing <code>cd my-website</code> in the terminal. Then, initialize a new Git repository by typing <code>git init</code>. Next, add all the files in the folder to the Git repository by typing <code>git add .</code>. Finally, commit the changes by typing <code>git commit -m "Initial commit"</code>.</p><p>Now, connect your local Git repository to the remote GitHub repository by typing <code>git remote add origin https://github.com/your-username/my-website.git</code>. Replace "your-username" with your GitHub username. Then, push the changes to GitHub by typing <code>git push -u origin main</code>.</p><p>Step 4: Deploying your website on Netlify
Now that your website is on GitHub, it's time to deploy it on Netlify. Netlify is a platform for hosting and deploying websites.</p><p>First, sign up for a free account on Netlify. Then, click the "New site from Git" button on the dashboard. Choose GitHub as the source and select the "my-website" repository. Then, click "Deploy site".</p><p>Netlify will build and deploy your website automatically. Once the deployment is complete, you'll be given a URL for your website. Click the URL to see your website live on the internet.</p><p>Congratulations, you've created your first website and deployed it on Netlify! This is just the beginning of your web development journey. Keep learning and exploring new technologies to take your skills to the next level.</p></div></div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="html" /><category term="website" /><category term="coding" /><category term="programming" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Creating your first website can be a daunting task, but with the right resources and tools, it can be an exciting and rewarding experience. In this blog post, we'll walk you through the process of creating a simple website for beginners and deploying it on Netlify.Step 1: Setting up your development environment Before you start building your website, you'll need to set up your development environment. You'll need a text editor to write your code, a web browser to test your website, and Git to manage your code.For this tutorial, we recommend using Visual Studio Code as your text editor and Google Chrome as your web browser. Git comes pre-installed on most operating systems, but if you don't have it installed, you can download it from the official website.Step 2: Creating your website Once you have your development environment set up, it's time to create your website. For this tutorial, we'll create a simple website that displays a heading and a paragraph.First, create a new folder on your computer and name it "my-website". Then, open Visual Studio Code and create a new file in the "my-website" folder. Name the file "index.html" and add the following code: &lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; &lt;html&gt; &lt;head&gt; &lt;title&gt;My Website&lt;/title&gt; &lt;/head&gt; &lt;body&gt; &lt;h1&gt;Welcome to my website&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is a paragraph.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/body&gt; &lt;/html&gt;]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:3000/assets/images/photo-1498050108023-c5249f4df085.avif" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:3000/assets/images/photo-1498050108023-c5249f4df085.avif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>